<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web-programming on Open Operational Research</title>
    <link>https://openor.blog/tags/web-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web-programming on Open Operational Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://openor.blog/tags/web-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life &amp; Death part 3</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/life-death-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/life-death-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Background From before I hit publish on part 2, I had people telling me that the graphs were cool and they wanted their version. I briefly considered making a page with 404 graphs on it - 2 graphs \(*\) 2 sexes \(*\) 101 age groups. Then I remembered that this is a webpage, not a static document, and Javascript is a thing. I discovered the rather useful htmlwidget plotly, which adds interactivity and drops some of the painful aspects of ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSM 2 - interactive maps</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/osm-2-interactive-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/osm-2-interactive-maps/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the leaflet package Plain images of map data is so web 1.0. R htmlwidgets mean I don’t have to acttuully learn Javascript to mess around with Javascript libraries in this site. One of the flagship examples leaflet works with OSM out of the box.
Last time I wrote a file containing name and distance of my coffee shops. I now need to run that script again so I can get longitude and latitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Organograms 3 - the meeting calculator</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-3-the-meeting-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-3-the-meeting-calculator/</guid>
      <description>I have data, I have a website. It’s hardly fair to ask you to take the numbers I’m spitting out of the Open Organograms series and put them in a calculator to do something useful with them. Thankfully, R markdown has a nice interface between the markdown and Javascript, called htmlwidgets.
Having generated a median salary for (so far 2) departments, I think it might be interesting to see a meeting calculator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>