<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open-Organograms on Open Operational Research</title>
    <link>https://openor.blog/tags/open-organograms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open-Organograms on Open Operational Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://openor.blog/tags/open-organograms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Organograms 3 - the meeting calculator</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-3-the-meeting-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-3-the-meeting-calculator/</guid>
      <description>I have data, I have a website. It’s hardly fair to ask you to take the numbers I’m spitting out of the Open Organograms series and put them in a calculator to do something useful with them. Thankfully, R markdown has a nice interface between the markdown and Javascript, called htmlwidgets.
Having generated a median salary for (so far 2) departments, I think it might be interesting to see a meeting calculator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Organograms 2 - the rise of the tibble</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-2-the-rise-of-the-tibble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/open-organograms-2-the-rise-of-the-tibble/</guid>
      <description>##Background I learned data.table before tidyverse. It can be hard to read, and I’m always forgetting commas. I’m making an effort to learn the tidyverse, and I am already impressed with dplyr and tibble. (I’ve been impressed with ggplot2 for a while now.)
I’ve seen benchmarks that suggests data.table is about 2ce as fast as tibble. It’s also the case that the code run time is a tiny fraction of my overall project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Organograms</title>
      <link>https://openor.blog/post/2018-03-26-open-organograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openor.blog/post/2018-03-26-open-organograms/</guid>
      <description>##Background
One of the reasons I’ve founded this site is because I’ve discovered https://data.gov.uk/ and I have ideas. In particular, I won’t discuss outside of work anything I only know through work, so it was nice to see pay data in the public sphere.
Full background is at http://guidance.data.gov.uk/organogram-data.html but basically, the Prime Minister decided that the public deserve the structure and hierarchy of the Government Departments, and a few agencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>